Lewis Connolly





Sep 2023 - Sep 2024



07889462020 lewis.connolly92@gmail.com Dundee, Scotland

Software developer and experienced IT professional with a Master's in Computer Games Technology (Distinction) and an Honours degree in Computer Science. Over 10 years in IT Operations, specialising in automation across diverse technologies. Strong teamwork and communication skills, with a passion for continuous learning.

Education

Grade: Distinction MSc Computer Games Technology Abertay University

Notable modules and grades:

Programming for Games: A+

 Advanced Procedural Methods: A Game Design and Development: A

 Research Methods: A+ Master's Project: B+

Network Game Development: B

Sep 2008 - Sep 2012 Grade: 2:1

BSc Hons Computer Science Heriot-Watt University

Academic transcripts available on request.

Skills

C#, C++, Unity, Unreal Engine, DirectX 11, DirectXTK, HLSL, ShaderLab, RenderDoc, Git, SDL, SFML, Python, PowerShell, Blender, Applied Mathematics

Projects Œ

Viva Las Mages Feb - Apr 2024

Student Game Development Project

As the lead programmer and co-designer in a team of 7 (consisting of artists, designers and an audio specialist), developed a vertical slice of a game (playtime ~25 minutes) over 12 weeks based on a novel concept featuring dungeon exploration, card playing, and risk-reward mechanics.

Responsibilities included:

- All programming except audio.
- Gameplay and level design.
- UI design and implementation.
- Version control.

Master's Project

May - August 2024

Procedural Cave Generation

As part of a dissertation, developed an application within Unity to procedurally generate 3D caves containing stalagmites and stalactites using cellular automata and isosurface algorithms.

Implemented features included:

- Multithreaded Cellular Automata algorithm.
- Marching Cubes 33 algorithm.
- Dual Contouring algorithm utilising a quadratic error function and singular value decomposition.
- Stalagmite and stalactite generation.
- Tessellation and Phong smoothing.
- Perlin Noise-based vertex displacement.
- Texture blending based on surface angle.



Employment History

IT Infrastructure Engineer Zonal Retail Data Systems

Sep 2017 - Present

Hospitality Technology Solutions Provider

- Responsible for helping to increase the performance and resilience of an extensive infrastructure platform, with a focus on automation, virtualisation, storage and backup solutions.
- Developed PowerShell scripting solutions to automate processes (such as configuring servers and virtual machines), monitor critical infrastructure, and solve problems in an efficient and repeatable manner.
- Produced documentation and delivered presentations to explain and demonstrate concepts and solutions to fellow engineers and management.

Multiple IT infrastructure roles

Nov 2013 - Mar 2017

Hewlett-Packard/Hewlett Packard Enterprise/DXC Technology

IT Services and Consulting

- Joined graduate programme and held positions of Peripherals Integration Engineer, Build Integration Engineer, and Build Engineer which became a permanent, non-graduate role.
- Installed and maintained hardware and software in non-production data centre environments used as development, integration and testing platforms.
- In collaboration with a colleague, hosted presentations and site tours for work experience students on a regular basis.

References

Available on request.